futurism.com 2019-05-06

# Futurism - Privacy Policy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for Futurism, LLC (“Futurism”) when you interact with us via our website, email, and other online services where we post content (our “Services”). This privacy policy will notify you of the following:

  1. What information is collected from you through the web site, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
  2. What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
  3. The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.
  4. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

This Policy applies to Futurism and our websites, emails we send, as well as the information we collect when you interact with us through social media or other websites and online services. It does not apply to non-Futurism websites and mobile applications that may link to the Services or be linked to or from the Services; please review the privacy policies on those websites and applications directly to understand their privacy practices.

 **Information Collection, Use, and Sharing**

 _Information You Give Us_

Some of the Services may include features or services that permit you to enter contact information and other information about you. We collect and store any information you enter on our Services. This may include your name, mailing address, ZIP code, phone number, or email address.

We will use your information to communicate with you, including to respond to your inquiries, and to provide you with email bulletins if you have subscribed. While we may utilize service providers to assist in these activities, we will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request. We will not sell or rent information you give us to anyone.

 _Information We Collect Automatically_

When you interact with the Services, certain information about your use of our Services is automatically collected. This information includes computer and connection information, such as statistics on your page views, traffic to and from our Services, referral URL, ad data, your IP address, and device identifiers. This information also may include how you search for our Services, the websites you click on from our Services or emails, whether and when you open our emails, and your browsing activities across other websites.When you interact with us or the Services through a social media platform (such as by clicking on a social media icon linked from our Services), we may collect the personal information that you make available to us on that page, including your account ID or username and other information included in your posts. If you choose to log in to your account with or through a social networking service, we and that service may share certain information about you and your activities.

Much of this information is collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies, as well as through your web browser or device (e.g., IP address, MAC address, browser version, etc.). The tracking technologies employed when you use our Services may be first-party or third-party.

We use cookies to analyze how the Futurism website is accessed, used or is performing. We use this information to maintain, operate and continually improve the Futurism website. For example, we use Google Analytics to help us analyze how users interact with and use the Services, compile reports on the Services’ activity, and provide other services related to our Services’ activity and usage. To learn more about Google’s partner services and to learn how to opt out of tracking of analytics by Google, click [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

We may also obtain information from our e-mail newsletters, to learn whether you opened or forwarded the newsletter or clicked on any of the content. This information tells us about our newsletters’ effectiveness and helps us ensure that we’re delivering information that you find interesting.

We partner with third parties who use cookies to display interest-based advertising to you on the Services. Interest-based advertising is the collection of data across different websites and/or difference devices for the purpose of tailoring advertising based on preferences or interests know or inferred from the data collected. We partner with FreeStar to provide advertisements on our Services about products and services that may be of interest to you on our Services. Additional third parties, including Google, Facebook, and other social media platforms, may use tracking technologies on our website to collect or receive information from the Futurism websites and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads when you leave the Services.

While Futurism will not share information that personally identifies you with unaffiliated third parties for their own uses, such third parties may, with sufficient data from other sources, be able to personally identify you.

 **Your Access to and Control Over Information**  
You may opt out of any future email contacts from us at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number listed below.

You can learn more about ad serving companies and the options available to limit their collection and use of your information by visiting the websites for the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), and the [European Interactive Digital Advertising Initiative](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Similarly, you can learn about your options to opt-out of mobile app tracking by certain advertising networks through your device settings and by resetting the advertiser ID on your Apple or Android device. You can opt-out of targeted ads provided in partnership with FreeStar specifically by visiting FreeStar’s [website](https://freestar.io/data-policy/).

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to disable or reject cookies. If you delete your cookies or if you set your browser to decline cookies, some features of the Services may not be available, work, or work as designed.

Please note that opting-out of advertising networks services does not mean that you will not receive advertising while using our Services or on other websites, nor will it prevent the receipt of interest-based advertising from third parties that do not participate in these programs. It will, however, exclude you from interest-based advertising conducted through participating networks, as provided by their policies and choice mechanisms. If you delete your cookies, you may also delete your opt-out preferences.

You may also contact us to:

  * See what data we have collected directly from you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have collected directly from you.
  * Have us delete any data we have collected directly from you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

 **Additional Information About our Data Collection and Sharing Practices**

We may make changes to this Policy from time to time. We will post any changes, and such changes will become effective when they are posted. Your continued use of our Services following the posting of any changes will mean you accept those changes.

We or our partners may combine information from the Services together and with other information we obtain from our business records or from third party sources. We also may use or combine information that we collect from the Services with information provided by third parties, including demographic information and other attributes, and organizational affiliations.

We may change our ownership or corporate organization while providing the Services. We may transfer to another entity or its affiliates or service providers some or all information about you in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, acquisition, sale of assets or any line of business, change in ownership control, or financing transaction. We cannot promise that an acquiring party or the merged entity will have the same privacy practices or treat your information the same as described in this Policy.

We may use or disclose information about you if required to do so by law or on the good-faith believe that such sharing is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or our Services; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Services, or our users; or (c) act to protect the personal safety of our employees and agents, other users of the Services, or members of the public.

 **Security**  
We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

 ** _Information for Users in Europe and Elsewhere Outside the U.S._**

If you use our Services outside of the United States, you understand that we may collect, process, and store your personal information in the United States and other countries. The laws in the U.S. regarding personal information may be different from the laws of your state or country. Any such transfers will comply with safeguards as required by relevant law. If applicable, you may have a right to claim compensation for damages caused by a breach of relevant data protection laws.

 ** _Users in the European Union (EEA) and Switzerland_**

If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, the following information applies.

 _Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing_ : As explained above, we process personal data in various ways depending upon your use of our Services. We process personal data on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform our agreement to provide Services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the Services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedom related to data privacy.

 _Right to lodge a complaint_ : Users that reside in the EEA or Switzerland have the right to lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority concerned. Contact details for data protection authorities are available [here.](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm)

 _Transfers_ : Personal information we collect may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates or subcontractors maintain facilities. Upon the start of enforcement of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), we will ensure that transfers of personal information to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards as described in Article 46 of the GDPR.

 _Individual Rights_ : If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, you are entitled to the following rights once the GDPR becomes effective. **Please note** : In order to verify your identity, we may require you to provide us with personal information prior to accessing any records containing information about you.

  * The right to request data erasure. You have the right to have your data erased from our Services if the data is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, you withdraw consent and no other legal basis for processing exists, or you believe your fundamental rights to data privacy and protection outweigh our legitimate interest in continuing the processing.
  * The right to restrict or object to our processing. You have the right to restrict or object to our processing if we are processing your data based on legitimate interests or the performance of a task in the public interest as an exercise of official authority (including profiling); using your data for direct marketing (including profiling); or processing your data for purposes of scientific or historical research and statistics.

 ** _For Questions, or to Report a Problem_**

For questions about our privacy practices, contact us at:
